I'm going to teach you a quick and effective way to start soloing over any type of song
我将教你一种快速有效的方法来开始独奏任何类型的歌曲
and it's going to require the least amount of Music Theory possible and before we Dive
并且需要尽可能少的音乐理论知识，在我们深入之前
Right In be sure to stick around till the very end of the lesson because I've got a
一定要坚持到课程结束，因为我有一个
free gift for you and your guitar that you're gonna love okay so basically the soloing system
给你和你的吉他一份免费的礼物，你一定会喜欢的，基本上就是独奏系统
Narrows your options down to two basic musical categories major and minor and musically you
将您的选择范围缩小到两个基本音乐类别：大调和小调，以及音乐上您
can say a whole lot with just major and minor so we're going to start there what it'll also
只用大调和小调就能表达很多东西，所以我们将从这里开始
do is help you narrow down what tonality you should go for whenever you hear a track that
这样做是为了帮助你缩小你应该选择的音调，当你听到一个音轨时
you want to solo over okay so now let's relate this whole thing to the fretboard so let's
你想独奏，好吧，现在让我们把这整个事情与指板联系起来，让我们
say we're in the key of A all right and we want to have our major and minor tonalities
假设我们现在处于 A 调，我们想要有大调和小调
what we're going to be using are these simple four note groups that we're going to be able
我们将要使用的就是这些简单的四音符组，我们将能够
to span over three octaves so starting for in the key of A we're going to start with
跨越三个八度，所以我们从 A 调开始
the minor tonality right which is actually going to be borrowing just a fragment of the
右边的小调实际上只是借用了
minor pentatonic scale we're going to start with the fifth fret on the D string then seventh
小调五声音阶，我们将从 D 弦的第五品开始，然后是第七品
fret and then fifth fret and seventh fret on the G string so just those four notes is
然后是 G 弦上的第五品和第七品，所以只有这四个音符
what we're going to be working with and you may be wondering hey four notes isn't enough
我们将要讨论的内容，你可能会想，四个音符不够
to make a solo believe me it is so what we're going to do is we're going to take this for
为了让独奏相信我，所以我们要做的是，我们要把它当作
note grouping we're going to expand it across three octaves so we happen to be in currently
音符分组，我们将把它扩展到三个八度，所以我们现在恰好处于
the middle octave with this position here so what we're going to do is find the lower
中间八度音阶，我们要做的是找到较低的
Octave of these four notes so how to do that we're just going to shift down two Frets one
这四个音符的八度音程，所以我们只需向下移动两个音品
two and then down two strings one two and we're going to play that exact same thing
两根弦，然后向下拨动两根弦，一二，然后我们再弹奏同样的乐曲
and now we've found we've played that exact pattern and now we found those notes so we're
现在我们发现我们已经演奏了那个确切的模式，现在我们找到了那些音符，所以我们
going to be third fret and fifth fret on low E and then third and fifth on a same as these
将在低 E 上进行第三品和第五品，然后在与这些相同的第三品和第五品上进行
now we're going to find the upper octave okay so what we're going to do is we're going to
现在我们要找到高八度，所以我们要做的是
shift over three Frets right from the seventh fret here on the G string shift over three
移位三品 从 G 弦第七品向右移位三品
Frets and then go down two strings one two and then we have
品格，然后向下两根弦，一二，然后我们有
now we're in the neighborhood of that third octave so it's eighth fret tenth fret on B
现在我们处于第三个八度附近，所以它是 B 上的第八品和第十品
and eight ten on high e so we now have these four notes in three octaves
和高 e 上的八十，所以我们现在有三个八度的四个音符
and this is just the minor tonality right this is more than enough to craft a solo just
这只是小调，对吧，这足以创作一首独奏曲
to prove it to you before I even throw on any backing tracks I'm going to go ahead and
为了向你证明这一点，在我播放任何背景音乐之前，我要继续
just you know just I don't know play something see what happens [Music] so that's our minor
只是你知道只是我不知道播放一些东西看看会发生什么[音乐]所以这是我们的小
portion of this right and we use what I like to call the three for one octave system right
我们使用我喜欢称之为“三个八度音阶系统”的方法
where we have just this one little box of notes and then we expanded it across three
我们只有一个小盒子的笔记，然后我们将其扩展到三个
octaves right so we're getting three for one we get this middle octave is upper octave
八度音阶对吧，所以我们得到三个，我们得到这个中间八度音阶是高八度音阶
then this lower octave and now we get to learn the major portion of this which uses the same
然后是低八度，现在我们要学习的是使用相同
system right we're just going to adjust where it sits on the fretboard so we're going to
系统对吧，我们只是要调整它在指板上的位置，所以我们要
shift from over here right when we were on between uh the fourth sorry the fifth and
从这里转移，就在我们第四个，抱歉，第五个和
seventh Frets we're going to be shifting down one two three three Frets here so in this
第七品位，我们将在这里向下移动一二三三品位，因此在这个
now middle octave area in the major tonality it's between the second and fourth Frets on
现在大调中的中间八度区域位于第二和第四品之间
the D and G string for this middle octave part anyway right so we have second fret fourth
无论如何，这个中间八度部分的 D 和 G 弦对吧，所以我们有第二品第四品
fret on D second fret fourth fret on G so those are our four notes that we're going
在 D 上按第二品，在 G 上按第四品，这就是我们要演奏的四个音符
to expand using the three for one octave system so finding the lower octave we're going to
使用三个八度音程系统进行扩展，因此找到我们要找到的较低八度音程
shift down two Frets one two and then down two strings or sorry up two strings one two
向下移动两个音品一二，然后向下移动两根弦，或者向上移动两根弦一二
and then we're actually going to be entering into the territory of open strings so we got
然后我们实际上将进入开放弦的领域，所以我们得到
open E then second fret open a second fret so same as these notes
打开 E 然后第二品打开第二品所以与这些音符相同
right and just to kind of show you even though it's open strings just to show you how the
对，只是为了向你展示，即使它是开放的弦，只是为了向你展示
pattern would have would look just like this right if this happened to be a fret over here
如果这恰好是这里的音品，图案看起来就会像这样
and so if we're going to find the upper octave right we shift over three Frets one two three
所以如果我们要找到右边的高八度，我们需要移动三个品格一二三
and then down two strings one two and then now we have seven and uh sorry Fifth and seventh
然后沿着两根弦一二，然后现在我们有七，呃，对不起，第五和第七
Frets on the B and high e strings all right so that's our three for one octave system
B 弦和高 e 弦上的音品都很好，这就是我们的三弦八度音阶系统
right for the major notes in the key of A [Music] and just like with the minor ones
适合 A 调的大调音符，就像小调音符一样
we can totally make a viable solo just using the major portion but let's put this to the
我们完全可以只用主要部分来制作一个可行的独奏，但让我们把它放到
test I'd say we have plenty of options to create a nice solo using major and minor tonalities
测试我想说我们有很多选择，可以用大调和小调来创作一首优美的独奏曲
now which you're actually going to be using and to what ratio you're going to be using
现在你实际上要使用什么以及要使用的比例是多少
each one really depends on the style of the track you're playing over but we're going
每一个都取决于你播放的曲目的风格，但我们会
to start with a blues track since it's pretty uh common to go back and forth to uh for major
先从布鲁斯音乐开始，因为来回切换大调是很常见的
and minor almost on an equal level so let's see how that works out
和次要的几乎处于同等水平，所以让我们看看结果如何
foreign
外国的
[Music] foreign
[外国音乐]
[Music] so in that example I was sticking with what we just learned and adding some
[音乐] 所以在这个例子中，我坚持我们刚刚学到的内容，并添加了一些
Liberties here and there as far as embellishing the notes you know so you don't want to just
随意地修饰一下音符，你知道，所以你不想只是
you don't want to do that because it's just static and it doesn't feel musical the whole
你不会想这样做，因为它只是静态的，而且整体感觉不到音乐性
point of breaking the notes up like this and not using just a singular scale pattern is
像这样分解音符而不是只使用单一音阶模式的意义在于
because this type of layout kind of forces you to not noodle so much right it's easy
因为这种布局迫使你不要做太多的事情，这很容易
to to go up and down a scale in a linear fashion when you have all of the the notes laid out
当你把所有音符都摆好后，以线性方式上下移动音阶
in a very ergonomic pattern but in this case they're a little more spread out right and
非常符合人体工程学的图案，但在这种情况下，它们分布得更开一些，
it's just the same four notes and three octaves so it forces you a little bit more to really
都是同样的四个音符和三个八度，所以它迫使你更努力地去真正
milk those notes and find some creative uses of of them and that's why I say you know you
充分利用这些笔记，找到一些创造性的用途，这就是为什么我说你知道你
have full uh full uh uh you know free reign to do little things like bends vibrato slides
有充分的自由，可以做一些小事情，比如弯曲颤音滑音
that kind of thing just to make them seem interesting and feel authentic and hey real
这类事情只是为了让它们看起来有趣，感觉真实，嘿，真实
quick if you're getting a lot of value out of this lesson be sure to hit that like button
如果你从本课中获益良多，请务必点击“赞”按钮
and consider subscribing to our YouTube channel if you haven't already it really helps us
如果你还没有订阅我们的 YouTube 频道，请考虑订阅，这对我们很有帮助
out and lets me know that you're enjoying these lessons that I should be making more
让我知道你很喜欢这些课程，我应该多做一些
of them for you all right let's get back to it with the blues we were able to get away
...
with the more equal ratio between major and minor but let's switch to something that really
heavily prefers one or the other [Music] thank you [Music]
...
[Music] [Applause] [Music]
so in that example that was more of a pop rock style backing track definitely favored
...
the major tonality more so than the minor but I still wanted to find places to you know
throw the miner in there even though it was going to be in select spots so I try to just
...
lean heavily on major and then when the backing track shifted a little bit then maybe that
was a good time to just kind of throw in a little bit of minor but I kind of had a feeling
...
that if I stayed there too long it would just start sounding a little too bluesy and it
would no longer fit the style of the track and by the way the key of that backing track
...
was the key of E so I adjusted accordingly to fit that key so where I was essentially
if we were to start with the minor tonality further up here on the fretboard uh the middle
...
octave part is going to be 12 and 14 on dng
all right and then the lower octave is going to be between 10 and 12 on the A and low E
...
string all right and then in the upper octave three Frets over one two three down two strings
so between 15 and 17 on the B and high e strings [Music] and for the major tonality we're going
所以在 B 弦和高音 e 弦上，音调在 15 到 17 之间。对于大调，我们将
to be between the 9th and 11th Frets on the d and g strings that's in the middle Octave
位于 d 弦和 g 弦的第 9 和第 11 品之间，即中间八度
of it then lower octave is between uh seven and nine on low E and A right upper octave
那么低八度在低 E 上的七到九之间，右上八度
is going to be between 12 and 14 on B and high e
在 B 和高 e 上将在 12 到 14 之间
and now as a final example why don't we switch to a style of backing track that tends to
现在作为最后一个例子，我们为什么不切换到一种倾向于
favor more minor pentatonic than major [Music] [Applause] [Music]
更喜欢小调五声音阶而不是大调五声音阶 [音乐] [掌声] [音乐]
oh
哦
[Music] so in that example is more of a straight ahead rock kind of sound right which I think
[音乐] 所以在这个例子中，它更像是一种直接的摇滚风格，我认为
tends to favor minor pentatonic because minor pentatonic sounds a little meaner you know
倾向于小调五声音阶，因为小调五声音阶听起来更粗犷一些
when you start getting into the major tonality it brings in that sort of happy sound which
当你开始进入大调时，它会带来那种快乐的声音
you know isn't always the most rock and roll so what I did there was kind of the inverse
你知道并不总是最摇滚的，所以我做的是相反的
of what I did in the previous track I was leaning heavy on the minor pentatonic right
我在上一首曲目中所做的是，我主要依靠小调五声音阶右
using the minor tonality of our little system here and then once I felt like I could throw
使用我们这里的小系统的小调，然后当我感觉我可以抛出
in just a little bit of major stuff here just to quote it and then go right back to the
这里只引用一点重要内容，然后直接回到
minor pentatonic so that it kind of came home before it got a little too distracting where
小调五声音阶，这样它就能在变得有点太分散注意力之前回到原点。
I was just spending way too much time in the major tonality and as you may have noticed
我只是在大调上花了太多时间，你可能已经注意到了
that backing track brought us right back to the key of A so to sum it all up this simple
那首背景音乐把我们带回到了 A 调，所以总结起来很简单
method of soloing allows you to play over any style of song all you have to do is think
独奏方法可以让你演奏任何风格的歌曲，你所要做的就是思考
to yourself does this prefer major or minor and of course if you don't really know just
你自己喜欢主修还是辅修，当然如果你真的不知道
by listening you can just start playing and just use trial and error kind of decide for
通过聆听，你可以开始演奏，然后通过反复尝试来决定
yourself because your ears will tell you if something sounds good or not if something
因为你的耳朵会告诉你某件东西听起来好不好，如果某件东西听起来不好，
works musically or not so you know trust your instincts and if you find that you know you
不管音乐是否有效，你都要相信你的直觉，如果你发现你知道你
tend to prefer how the major tonality sounds over a specific style of track or how minor
倾向于喜欢大调音阶听起来比特定风格的曲目或小调音阶听起来
tonality sounds over another style of track that'll kind of help you narrow things down
音调听起来比另一种风格的曲目更能帮助你缩小范围
so that way in the future when you start playing over tracks of similar Styles you already
这样，当你将来开始播放类似风格的曲目时，你已经
kind of have an inventory of like what's going to work between major and minor and you don't
有点像在主要和次要之间有一个清单，但你没有
even have to worry about getting too into the weeds as far as um you know those like
甚至不必担心陷入困境，就像你知道的
even more complex tonalities like like using the modes and stuff like that that's all great
甚至更复杂的音调，比如使用模式之类的，都很棒
and that stuff will obviously come but you know right now major and minor you can cover
这些事情显然会出现，但你知道现在你可以涵盖主要和次要的事情
a whole lot of ground I could argue most of the what you know as far as music just goes
我可以争论一下你所知道的大部分关于音乐的知识
between those two so you got more than enough to work with right now now what if I told
在这两者之间，所以你现在有足够多的东西可以做，如果我告诉你
you that you can take what you learned today and apply it to any musical key you can pass
你可以把今天学到的知识运用到任何你能传授的音乐调上。
possibly think of and expand it even further so that you're playing not only over any song
可能会想到并进一步扩展它，这样你不仅可以演奏任何歌曲
but you're playing it with Comfort ease and confidence now I just so happen to have the
但你现在玩起来很轻松、很自信，我恰好有
very thing that'll get you there remember that free gift I was telling you about well
能让你到达那里的东西记得我告诉你的免费礼物
got it right here this bad boy is the fretboard conveyor belt it's a system that has helped
没错，这个坏男孩就是指板传送带，这是一个帮助的系统
thousands of guitar players online learn how to name the notes on the fretboard and play
...
in any musical key under the sun and you're going to get a free copy today be sure to
click here to claim that free copy or check the link in the description box and with that
...
said I want to thank you for hanging out with me today I hope you've enjoyed this lesson
as much as I've enjoyed bringing it to you I'm Eddie with guitar Mastery method and I
...
look forward to seeing you in the next lesson [Music] foreign